Guide to the James H. Karales photographs, 1953-2006 and undated RL.10017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
James H. Karales photographs
1953-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Karales, James H.
RL.10017
18 Linear Feet Approximately 15,000 items
James Karales was an American photojournalist on staff at Look magazine. Collection houses the archive of photojournalist James Karales, active from the 1950s to the 1980s. The majority of the images in the collection originated from his work for Look magazine during the 1960s. Major projects document Rendville, Ohio, a coal mining town and one of the first racially integrated towns in Appalachia; the Vietnam War; New York's Lower East Side; Oregon logging; and the 1960s Civil Rights movement, including photographs of Martin Luther King, Jr. There may be racially mixed persons appearing in the Rendville series. Smaller projects document California, New Mexico, the Andrea Doria disaster, and other subjects. Formats in the collection include contact sheets, which serve as a thumbnail guide to almost all of the prints and negatives in the collection; black-and-white proof prints and finished prints in a range of sizes; original negatives (closed to research use); and over 1100 color slides. There are also print and biographical materials, some correspondence, and audiovisual materials. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Collection Overview
The majority of the images in the collection originated from his work for Look magazine during the 1960s. His major projects include images from Rendville, Ohio, a coal mining town and one of the first racially integrated towns in Appalachia; the Vietnam War; New York's Lower East Side; Oregon logging and the timber industry; and important individuals and events of the 1960s Civil Rights movement, including photographs of Martin Luther King, Jr. and activities of the Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee. There may be racially mixed persons appearing in the Rendville and Lower East Side series. Other smaller projects include images of California, New Mexico, the Andrea Doria, and other subjects.
There are also supporting materials that include Karales' curriculum vitae; essays on photography and teaching; publicity for exhibits and other events; correspondence with publishers; digitized images from the Vietnam War on a CD; and clippings, magazine layouts, and other materials related to Karales' published work. An audiocassette contains remarks on Karales' life and works by Sam Stephenson at the opening of an exhibit of Karales' work at Duke University.
Formats in the collection include contact sheets; proof prints and finished prints ranging from 8 1/2 x 14 to 16 x 20 inches; original negatives (closed to research use); and over 1100 color slides. Unless otherwise noted, the photographic items are arranged in the following sequence in each series: contact sheets, prints (from smallest to largest), slides, negatives, and finally, duplicates. There are also digital jpeg files for selected images in certain series (Vietnam, Rendville).
Biographical Note
James H. Karales was born in Canton, Ohio in 1930. In 1955, Karales graduated from Ohio University with BFA in photography. Upon graduation, he worked with W. Eugene Smith. Karales learned printing skills under Smith, while pursuing his own projects in Rendville and the Pacific Northwest. In 1960, he joined the staff at Look magazine, where he worked until it ceased publication in 1971, and where he took some of his most iconic pictures, documenting the Selma to Montgomery civil rights march, the Vietnam War, and the Lower East Side. Karales receieved numerous awards, such as the Overseas Press Club Award and the Picture of the Year. His photographs are housed in many collections, including the International Center of Photography, the High Museum, and the Museum of Modern Art. He passed away in April 2002.
Access Restrictions
Collection access restricted.
Negatives and original recordings are closed to use.
Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.
Provenance
The James H. Karales photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 2004-2009, with additional photographs received as a gift from the Gary Davis Collection in New York City in 2008, 2011, and 2012.
African Americans -- Photographs; Civil rights movements -- Alabama -- Photographs; Civil rights movements -- United States -- 20th century -- Photographs; Coal mines and mining -- Ohio; Documentary Photography -- United States; Logging -- Northwest, Pacific; Photojournalists -- United States; Timber industry -- Northwest, Pacific; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Photographs; Alabama -- Photographs; Appalachian region -- Photographs; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.) -- Photographs; Montgomery (Ala.) -- History -- Photographs; Northwest, Pacific -- Photographs; Rendville (Ohio) -- Photographs; Selma (Ala.) -- History -- Photographs; United States -- Race relations; Vietnam (Republic) -- Photographs; Black-and-white prints (photographs); Negatives (photographs); Gelatin silver prints; Contact sheets; Slides (photographs); CD-ROMs; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); Look (serial); King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Heschel, Abraham Joshua; Karales, James H.; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957, 5 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  These images represent James Karales' first major photojournalistic work, a study of a small mining town in Ohio which was one of the first racially integrated towns in the U.S. Subjects include white and African American adults and children, families, miners at work, houses, local stores, street scenes, landscapes, and social gathering places such as churches and dance halls. Racially mixed people may appear in some images.
  In 1958, Edward Steichen bought some of the Rendville pictures for the Museum of Modern Art and Helen Gee exhibited the photographs at the Limelight Gallery in Greenwich Village, marking this photographic work as a breakthrough for Karales.
  Series includes contact sheets, small work prints, large finished prints, and negatives (closed to use), all black-and-white. Prints are marked on the back with the photographer's original image identifier and whenever possible they are arranged in that identifier order, which also usually reflects a rough chronological order. A CD with jpeg files of selected images is included in the series; files have been migrated to a library server.
  - Rendville Contact Sheets, 8 folders, 114 prints
    No job numbers have been identified for the Rendville photographic work. The 114 contact sheets include Karales' markings indicating images selected for proof prints or finished prints. Film roll numbers represented: 1-40 and 1A-5A. Of the 114 contact sheets, there is a set of 63 duplicate sheets.
    - Contact sheets: roll numbers 1-40, 1A-5A, and duplicates (Box 1)
  - Rendville Work Prints, 34 folders; 417 prints
    Contains 52 4x6 and 365 5x7 work prints. Numbers represent rolls and frames, and are marked on the backs of the prints. Of the 52 4x6 prints, 29 are duplicates; of the 365 5x7 prints, 140 are duplicates. Folders are titled with the roll numbers housed within.
    - Work prints: roll numbers 1-18, 20-20; 1A, 2A, and 5A (Box 1-2)
  - Rendville Negatives Series, 50 negative folders
    Approximately 250 negative strips representing film rolls 1 through 40 and 1A through 10A. Negative folders are labeled with roll numbers.
    - Negatives: roll numbers 1-40 and 1A-10A (Box 3)
  - Rendville Finished Prints, 32 prints
    Contains 32 black-and-white gelatin silver prints selected from the thousands of images Karales shot in Rendville, Ohio in the 1950s. Some prints are mounted on board. All titles supplied by library staff.
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-001)
      Legacy identifiers: 3:34; GDC 2613
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-002)
      Legacy identifiers: 20:13; GDC 2693
      Same content as print RL-10017-P044 (16 x 20 inches).
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-003)
      Legacy identifiers: 22:11; GDC 2685
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (8 x 13.5 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-004)
      Legacy identifiers: 23:4; GDC 2709
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (9 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-005)
      Legacy identifiers: 23:8; GDC 2700
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-006)
      Legacy identifiers: 24:12; GDC 2576
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (8 x 10 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-007)
      Legacy identifiers: 24:35; GDC 2757
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-008)
      Legacy identifiers: 27:11; GDC 2551
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-009)
      Legacy identifiers: 28:28; GDC 2679
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-010)
      Legacy identifiers: 29:4; GDC 2604
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-011)
      Legacy identifiers: 29 34; GDC 2678
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-012)
      Legacy identifiers: 35:4; GDC 2680
      Same content as print RL-10017-P046 (16 x 20 inches).
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-013)
      Legacy identifiers: 35:18; GDC 2539
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-014)
      Legacy identifiers: 35:30; GDC 2577
      Same content as print RL-10017-P047 (17 x 21 inches).
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-015)
      Legacy identifiers: 35:30; GDC 2661
      Copy of RL-10017-P014; same content as print RL-10017-P047 (17 x 21 inches).
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-016)
      Legacy identifiers: 38:26; GDC 2660
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (9 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-017)
      Legacy identifiers: 40:unnumbered; GDC 2708
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-018)
      Legacy identifiers: 1A:4; GDC 2692
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-019)
      Legacy identifiers: 1A:19; GDC 2681
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-020)
      Legacy identifiers: 2A:18; GDC 2683
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-021)
      Legacy identifiers: 4A: unnumbered; GDC 2697
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-022)
      Legacy identifiers: 5A:5; GDC 2698
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (9.5 x 13 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-023)
      Legacy identifiers: 5A:6; GDC 2706
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-024)
      Legacy identifiers: 5A:10; GDC 2652
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-025)
      Legacy identifiers: 5A:12; GDC 2659
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-026)
      Legacy identifiers: 5A:14; GDC 2699
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-027)
      Legacy identifiers: 6A:24; GDC 2684
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-028)
      Legacy identifiers: 7A:9; GDC 2696
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-029)
      Legacy identifiers: 8A:5; GDC 2687
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-030)
      Legacy identifiers: 8A:40; GDC 2550
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-031)
      Legacy identifiers: 8A:41; GDC 2552
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-032)
      Legacy identifiers: 8A:42; GDC 2656
      Same content as print RL-10017-P049 (16 x 20 inches).
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-033)
      Legacy identifiers: 9A: unnumbered; GDC 2686
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-034)
      Legacy identifiers: 9A: unnumbered; GDC 2695
      Copy of RL-10017-P033.
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-035)
      Legacy identifiers: 9A: unnumbered; GDC 2690
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-036)
      Legacy identifiers: 10A: unnumbered; GDC 2603
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-037)
      Legacy identifiers:; GDC 2575
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-038)
      Legacy identifiers:; GDC 2622
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-039)
      Legacy identifiers:; GDC 2646
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-040)
      Legacy identifiers:; GDC 2670
      Same content as print RL-10017-P051 (16 x 20 inches).
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-041)
      Legacy identifiers:; GDC 2702
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (8.5 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-042)
      Legacy identifiers:; GDC 2704
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-043)
      Legacy identifiers: 12 15
      Mounted.
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-044)
      Legacy identifiers: 20:13; GDC 2778
      Same content as print RL-10017-P002 (11 x 14 inches); mounted.
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-045)
      Legacy identifiers: 20:27; GDC 2781
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-046)
      Legacy identifiers: 35:4
      Same content as print RL-10017-P012 (11 x 14 inches); mounted.
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-047)
      Legacy identifiers: 35:30
      Same content as prints RL-10017-P014 (11 x 14 inches) and RL-10017-P015 (11 x 14 inches); mounted.
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-048)
      Legacy identifiers: 2A:5
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-049)
      Legacy identifiers: 8A:42; Karales-p-01
      Same content as print RL-10017-P032 (11 x 14 inches); mounted.
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-050)
      Legacy identifiers:
    - Rendville, Ohio, 1953-1957; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-051)
      Legacy identifiers:; Karales-p-03
      Same content as print RL-10017-P040 (11 x 14 inches); mounted.
- Logging, 1958-1959, 7 boxes
  Black-and-white images taken by Karales early in his career for a Weyerhauser lumber company assignment portray a full range of activities associated with logging in Oregon in the 1950s. Subjects feature individual loggers, logging crews and camp scenes, landscapes and aerial views of forested and logged areas, log driving, logging equipment, and logging activities on land and on a river. Identified geographic locations include Oregon (where apparently most if not all the scenes were shot), and Mt. Hood. The images are artistically compelling, featuring complex interplays of light and dark, and highlighting the placement of humans against natural landscapes and the giant trees they were felling.
  This series houses many "jobs" or photo shoots, to which Karales assigned an alpha or alphanumeric code. Print numbers consist of this code, roll number, and frame number. Prints are marked on the back with these original identifiers.
  - Logging Contact Sheets, 32 folders; 291 prints
    The 291 contact sheets include Karales' markings indicating images selected for proof prints or finished prints. In some cases there are individual frames cut from the original contact sheets. There are six duplicate sheets for AE6 and duplicates for job E rolls 1-42. Folders in boxes are marked with roll numbers.
    - Contact sheets: Job AE6, rolls 1-33; Job C267940 (5 sheets, no rolls numbers indicated); Job E, rolls 1-70; Job AE, rolls 48-70; and Job WC/NE, rolls 116-164; and duplicates (Box 4-5)
  - Logging Work Prints, 4x6 and 5x7, 39 folders; 682 prints
    Contains 33 4x6 and 649 5x7 work and proof prints. Numbers represent rolls and frames, and are marked on the backs of the prints. Folders in boxes are titled with the roll numbers housed within. There are seven folders of duplicate sheets.
    - Work prints, 4x6 and 5x7: roll numbers AE 1-67 and duplicates (Box 5-7)
  - Logging Work Prints, 8x10, 25 folders; 30 prints
    Of the 30 large work prints, 6 are duplicates. Typically there is only one image from each roll in this size, with a few exceptions.
    - Work prints, 8x10: roll numbers AE 1, 6, 7, 11-14, 17, 18, 22, 22, 27, 31, 32; E 1, E 13; WC/NE 116, 123, 126, 131, 140 (Box 7)
  - Logging Negatives, 97 negative folders
    Approximately 350 negative strips in 70 folders representing film rolls AE 1-70, and 27 folders of large-format 8x10 negatives from various Job C267940 rolls. Negative folders are labeled with roll numbers. All negatives are on safety film.
    Conditions Governing Use note
    Original negatives are closed to research use.
    - Negatives: roll numbers C267940:1-10; 1-40 and 1A-10A (Box 7-8)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Negatives in Box 7 are on ANSCO safety film.
  - Logging Finished Prints
    Original titles supplied by library staff.
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-052)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 6:3; GDC 2601
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-053)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 7:6; GDC 2638
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-054)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 19:26; GDC 2600
      Same content as print RL-10017-P078 (16 x 20 inches).
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-055)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 20:26; GDC 2597
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-056)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 34:11; GDC 2586
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-057)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 36:23; GDC 2610
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-058)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 36:30; GDC 2585
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-059)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 37:9; GDC 2591
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-060)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 37:32; GDC 2611
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-061)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 44:34; GDC 2636
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-062)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 45:30; GDC 2612
      Same content as print RL-10017-P082 (16 x 20 inches).
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-063)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 45:30; GDC 2637
      Copy of RL-10017-P062; same content as print RL-10017-P082 (16 x 20 inches).
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-064)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 45:31; GDC 2544
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-065)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 48:7; GDC 2589
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-066)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 48:27; GDC 2599
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-067)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 61:22; GDC 2596
      Same content as print RL-10017-P079.
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (8.5 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-068)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1; GDC 2546
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (8.5 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-069)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1; GDC 2623
      Copy of RL-10017-P068.
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-070)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1; GDC 2635
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (9 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-071)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1; GDC 2701
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-072)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 6 5:12; GDC 2590
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-073)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 6 5:12; GDC 2639
      Copy of RL-10017-P072.
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-074)
      Legacy identifiers: E 5:11; GDC 2584
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 24, Image RL-10017-P-075)
      Legacy identifiers: E 39:30; GDC 2594
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-076)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 2:35
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-077)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 7:6
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-078)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 9:26
      Same content as print RL-10017-P054 (11 x 14 inches); mounted.
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-079)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 16:22
      Same content as print RL-10017-P067 (11 x 14 inches); mounted.
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-080)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 25:31
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-081)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 28:22
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-082)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 1 45:30
    - Logging, Oregon, 1958-1959; (16 x 20 inches) (Box 27, Image RL-10017-P-083)
      Legacy identifiers: AE 6 30:5
- Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1960-1961, 2 boxes
  The Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee was organized in 1960 at Shaw University in Raleigh, North Carolina. Many (if not all) images were taken by Karales at a Passive Resistance Training in Atlanta, Georgia in 1960, for a Look magazine assignment. Images capture African American men and women participating in group training sessions, simulating arguments and giving or receiving feigned physical abuse; in some images there are white people present. The 20 large-format black-and-white prints are the only iamges in this series; there are no contact sheets or negatives.
  - SNCC Finished Prints
    Twenty black-and-white gelatin silver prints, ranging in size from 11x14 or 16x20 inches. All prints were acquired from the Gary Davis Gallery and are marked on the back with the donor's identifier; the prints are arranged in identifier order. Titles in brackets supplied by library staff.
    - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1960-1961; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 25, Image RL-10017-P-084)
      Legacy identifiers: GDC 2711
      Same content as print RL-10017-P096 (16 x 20 inches)
    - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1960-1961; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 25, Image RL-10017-P-085)
      Legacy identifiers: GDC 2712
      Same content as print RL-10017-P102 (16 x 20 inches)
    - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1960-1961; (11 x 14 inches) (Box 25, Image RL-10017-P-086)
      Legacy identifiers: GDC 2713